<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<rdf:RDF
    xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
    xmlns:aif="http://www.arg.dundee.ac.uk/aif#"
    xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#">
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#norecord">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">There is no record of viruses closely related to SARS-CoV-2 in any laboratory before December 2019, or genomes that in combination could provide a SARS-CoV-2 genome.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">No record of viruses closely related to SARS-CoV-2 in any laboratory</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#faeces">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Humans infected with SARS-CoV-2 shed virus through faeces and can have gastrointestinal symptoms, suggesting involvement of the gastrointestinal tract.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Humans shed SARS-CoV-2 through faeces</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#notcirculating">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">While there is some evidence for possible reintroduction of SARS-CoV-2 through handling of imported contaminated frozen products in China since the initial pandemic wave, this would be extraordinary in 2019 where the virus was not widely circulating.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Virus not widely circulating</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#infectionfromhumans">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">SARS-CoV-2 has been identified in an increasing number of animal species, but genetic and epidemiological studies have suggested that these were infections introduced from humans, rather than enzootic virus circulation.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Animal infections introduced from humans</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#hygiene">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Industrial food production has high levels of hygiene criteria and is regularly audited.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Food production hygiene</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#enteric">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Foodborne outbreaks with enteric viruses are common, and - when entering the food supply - may lead to geographically dispersed outbreaks that can be difficult to detect.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Foodborne outbreaks with enteric viruses are common</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#farmconnections">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">In high-density farms, there often are connections between farms (for instance, through the workforce and food supply), leading to complex transmission pathways that may be difficult to unravel, as was observed in other zoonotic outbreaks involving farmed animals.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">High-density farms</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#intermediate">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">SARS-CoV-2 is transmitted from an animal reservoir to an animal host, followed by subsequent spread within that intermediate host (spillover host), and then transmission to humans. The passage through an intermediate host can be with or without virus adaptation.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Introduction through intermediate host</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#noanimalinfection">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">There is no evidence of infection in any of the animals tested following the Wuhan outbreak.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">No animal infection</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#animalfarms">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">There was a large network of domesticated wild animal farms, supplying farmed wildlife to Wuhan.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Wild animal farms</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#pastexperience">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">The majority of emerging diseases originate from animal reservoirs and there is strong evidence that most of the current human coronaviruses have originated from animals.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Most human coronaviruses originate in animals</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#sewagevirus">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">These [enteric transmission] processes have been investigated widely for non-enveloped viruses but far less for enveloped viruses in the food chain, but there is widespread evidence for SARS-CoV-2 nucleic acid in sewage.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Evidence for SARS-CoV-2 nucleic acid in sewage</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#labmoved">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">The Wuhan CDC laboratory moved on 2nd December 2019 to a new location near the Huanan market. Such moves can be disruptive for the operations of any laboratory.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">The Wuhan CDC laboratory moved on 2nd December 2019</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#labinfection">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">When working in particular with virus cultures, but also with animal inoculations or clinical samples, humans could become infected in laboratories with limited biosafety, poor laboratory management practice, or following negligence.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Laboratory infection could happen</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#isolationrare">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Although many betacoronavirus sequences have been found in a range of bats, isolation of viruses from them is rare, and only a few of the identified full genomes have human ACE2 binding properties.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Isolation of viruses from bats is rare</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#hace">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">The RaTG13 and pangolin coronaviruses do bind to hACE2, although the fit is not optimal.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Animal coronavirus can bind to hACE2</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#bioengineered">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">There has been speculation regarding the presence of human ACE2 receptor binding and a furin-cleavage site in SARS-CoV-2, but both have been found in animal viruses as well, and elements of the furin-cleavage site are present in RmYN02 and the new Thailand bat SARSr-CoV.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Speculation about bio-engineering</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#farmingdensity">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">High-density farming is common in many places across the world and includes many livestock species as well as farmed wildlife.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">High-density farming</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#lab">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">SARS-CoV-2 is introduced through a laboratory incident, reflecting an accidental infection of staff from laboratory activities involving the relevant viruses.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Introduction through a laboratory incident</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#entericcov">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Many animal CoVs have dual respiratory and enteric tropism.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Animal CoV enteric tropism</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#noreintroduction">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Since the containment of SARS-CoV-2 in China, new outbreaks have occurred for which genomic sequence data was generated. Based on epidemiological analysis and genetic sequencing of viruses from new cases throughout 2020, there is no evidence of repeated introduction of early SARS-CoV-2 strains of potential animal origins into humans in China.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">No evidence of repeated introduction from animals</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#mink">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Seeding of SARS-CoV-2 in mink populations has shown that these animals are highly susceptible as well and the current evidence available cannot rule out the possibility for minks as the primary source of SARS-CoV-2.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Mink susceptible to SARS-CoV-2</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#seafood">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Seafood is known as a source of foodborne outbreaks, and food as a vehicle of zoonotic infections.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Seafood is known as a source of foodborne outbreaks</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#fomites">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Humans can also be exposed to contaminated fomites, as suggested from the studies on markets in China in 2020.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Humans exposed to contaminated fomites</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#sewagetreatment">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Sewage treatment typically does not remove all infectious viruses prior to release of wastewater in the environment.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Sewage treatment does not remove all viruses</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#package">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Screening programmes have found some limited evidence for the presence of SARS-CoV-2 by nucleotide acid tests in different batches of unopened packages and containers in different cities.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Screening of packaging</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#otheramplifiers">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Both these putative hosts are infrequently in contact with humans, and an intermediary step involving an amplifying host has been observed for several other emerging viruses (Henipaviruses, influenzaviruses, SARS-CoV and MERS-CoV). SARS-CoV-2 infection and intraspecies spread (including further transmission to humans) has been documented in an increasing number of animal species, particularly mustelids and felids.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Amplifying host for other viruses</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#coldoutbreak">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Since the near-elimination of SARS-CoV-2 in China, the country has experienced some outbreaks related to imported frozen products in 2020.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Outbreaks related to imported frozen products</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#pangolin">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Recently, two distinct types of SARSr-CoV were detected in Malayan pangolin (M. Javanica sampled in rescue centres in China for smuggled imported wildlife).</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Similar virus in pangolin</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#sewageearly">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">There is some literature suggesting SARS-CoV-2 may have been circulating earlier as indicated by sewage testing in Spain and Italy.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Sewage testing in Spain and Italy</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#bats">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Surveys of the bat virome conducted following the SARS epidemic in 2003 have found SARSr-CoV in various bats, particularly Rhinolophus bats, and viruses with the high genetic similarity to SARS-CoV-2 have been found in Rhinolophus bats sampled in China in 2013, Japan in 2013, Thailand in 2020 and Cambodia in 2010.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Similar virus in bats</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#direct">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">There is transmission of SARS-CoV-2 (or very closely-related progenitor virus) from an animal reservoir host to human, followed by direct person-to-person transmission with or without the need for adaptation of the virus to humans. The speed of dissemination will depend on chance events such as superspreading events.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Direct zoonotic transmission</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#livepackage">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">In the epidemiological investigation of Qingdao outbreak, the live virus was isolated from the outer package of imported frozen products.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Live virus on packaging</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#farmedanimals">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">The increasing number of animals shown to be susceptible to SARS-CoV-2 includes animals that are farmed in sufficient densities to allow potential for enzootic circulation.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Enzootic circulation</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#distance">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">The closest relatives of SARS-CoV-2 from bats and pangolin are evolutionarily distant from SARS-CoV-2.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Closest relatives of SARS-CoV-2 are evolutionarily distant</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#lowfoodrisk">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Risk-assessments have concluded that the risk of foodborne transmission of SARS-CoV-2 through these known transmission pathways is very low in comparison with respiratory transmission.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Low risk of foodborne transmission</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#distinct">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Because several contact residues between the bat and pangolin viruses and the hACE2 receptor are distinct from those in SARS-CoV-2, the affinity is low, and the viruses are genetically still quite distinct from SARS–CoV-2.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">SARSr-CoVs genetically distinct from SARS–CoV-2</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#wildfarmedtested">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Screening of farmed wildlife was limited but did not provide conclusive evidence for the existence of circulation.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">No evidence for SARS-CoV-2 in farmed wildlife</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#farmtransmission">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Optimized conditions for sustained virus transmission chains in large-scale animal farms may also impact on virus seasonality in favour of a year-round endemic transmission pattern, and thereby increasing the zoonotic risk in winter months.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Virus transmission chains in animal farms</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#foodsarsantibodies">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">For SARS, food animal handlers had increased prevalence of SARS-CoV-specific antibodies.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">SARS-CoV-specific antibodies in food animal handlers</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#resevoirbat">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Bats are a known reservoir for many zoonotic viruses (with high virus diversity globally); they have the highest proportion of projected zoonotic viruses of any mammalian order. In addition, bat ecology favours virus circulation (large populations, birthing waves, and closely spaced communities).</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Bats are a known reservoir</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#antibodybat">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Antibodies to bat coronavirus proteins have been found in humans with close contact to bats.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Antibodies to bat coronavirus</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#closesequence">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">The closest known CoV RaTG13 strain (96.2%) to SARS-CoV-2 detected in bat anal swabs have been sequenced at the Wuhan Institute of Virology.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">CoV RaTG13 strain sequenced at the Wuhan Institute of Virology</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#foodinconclusive">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">There is no conclusive evidence for foodborne transmission of SARS-CoV-2 and the probability of a cold-chain contamination with the virus from a reservoir is very low.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">No conclusive evidence for foodborne transmission</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#accidentshappen">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Although rare, laboratory accidents do happen, and different laboratories around the world are working with bat CoVs.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Laboratory accidents do happen</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#animalstested">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">There was no genetic or serological evidence for SARS-CoV-2 in a wide range of domestic and wild animals tested to date. The screening of the major livestock species was done across the country and provided no evidence for circulation of a related virus. The scale of testing in these species was such that widespread circulation is extremely unlikely.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">No evidence for SARS-CoV-2 in domestic and wild animals</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#lowconcentration">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Most viruses have been found in 2020 in low concentrations and are not amplified on cold-chain products. It is not clear what the infection route would be (possibly oral, touch, or aerosol).</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Low concentrations on cold-chain products</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#distancebat">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Although the closest related viruses have been found in bats, the evolutionary distance between these bat viruses and SARS-CoV-2 is estimated to be several decades, suggesting a missing link (either a missing progenitor virus, or evolution of a progenitor virus in an intermediate host).</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Evolutionary distance of bat virus</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#oralinfection">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Although typical foodborne infections are thought to be restricted to enteric pathogens, there is some evidence that the oral route could lead to infection for SARS-CoV-2 from hamster infection experiments, and the virus replicates in gut organoids.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Oral route could lead to infection</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#sewage">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Most evidence is for contamination of food with human viruses that are dispersed in growing areas through sewage or contaminated water for irrigation.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Sewage contamination</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#persistpackage">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">SARS-CoV-2 and related CoVs have been found to persist in conditions (time/temperature/humidity) found during trade of frozen products suggesting the virus could persist on contaminated frozen products.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Virus persists on packaging</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#similar">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Viruses similar to SARS-CoV-2 have been found in both pangolin and bats.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Similar virus in pangolin and bats</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#limitedsamples">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Regarding accidental culture, prior to December 2019, there is no evidence of circulation of SARS-CoV-2 among people globally and the surveillance programme in place was limited regarding the number of samples processed and therefore the risk of accidental culturing SARS-CoV-2 in the laboratory is extremely low.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Limited samples processed</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#distancepangolin">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Highly similar viruses have also been found in pangolins, suggesting cross-species transmission from bats at least once, but again with considerable genetic distance.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Evolutionary distance of pangolin virus</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#adaptsanimals">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">SARS-CoV-2 adapts relatively rapidly in susceptible animals (such as mink).</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">SARS-CoV-2 adapts in animals</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#biosafety">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">The three laboratories in Wuhan working with either CoVs diagnostics and/or CoVs isolation and vaccine development all had high quality biosafety level (BSL3 or 4) facilities that were well-managed, with a staff health monitoring programme with no reporting of COVID-19 compatible respiratory illness during the weeks/months prior to December 2019, and no serological evidence of infection in workers through SARS-CoV-2-specific serology-screening.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">High quality biosafety</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#cold">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">Food-chain transmission can reflect direct zoonotic transmission, or spillover through an intermediate host. Meanwhile cold chain products may be a vehicle of transmission between humans. The emphasis here is on cold/food chain products and their containers as potential route of introduction of SARS-CoV-2.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Introduction through the cold/food chain</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
  <aif:I-node rdf:about="https://dstl.github.io/eleatics/argumentation/coronavirus/information.xhtml#nomoveincident">
    <aif:claimText xml:lang="en">The Wuhan CDC lab which moved on 2nd December 2019 reported no disruptions or incidents caused by the move. They also reported no storage nor laboratory activities on CoVs or other bat viruses preceding the outbreak.</aif:claimText>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">No incidents caused by lab move</rdfs:label>
  </aif:I-node>
</rdf:RDF>
